Ain't Them Bodies Saints is a crime, drama,
romance film directed by David Lowery.
Bob Muldoon and Ruth Guthrie, an impassioned young outlaw couple on an extended crime
spree, are finally apprehended by lawmen after a shootout in the Texas hills.
Although Ruth wounds a local officer, Bob takes the blame.
But four years later, Bob escapes from prison and sets out to find
Ruth and their daughter, born during his incarceration.
Ruth Guthrie, played by Rooney Mara.
Bob Muldoon, played by Casey Affleck.
Patrick Wheeler, played by Ben Foster.
Skerritt, played by Keith Carradine.
Sylvie Guthrie, played by Kennadie Smith.
Sylvie Guthrie, played by Jacklynn Smith.
Ain't Them Bodies Saints is a 2013 American romantic crime
drama film written and directed by David Lowery.
The film stars Casey Affleck as Bob Muldoon, Rooney Mara as
Ruth Guthrie, and Ben Foster as Patrick Wheeler.
Bob (Affleck) and Ruth (Mara) are a couple who become involved in criminal
activities and are caught, with Bob taking the blame and going to prison.
The film follows the events after the criminal activities as Ruth gives
birth to their daughter, and the two live comfortably.
When the child is nearly four, Bob escapes from jail and
goes looking to reconnect with his family.
The film debuted at the 2013 Sundance Film Festival, where
it won the Cinematography Award in the U.S.
Dramatic Category and got nominated for the Grand Jury Prize.
It was selected to compete in the Critics' Week
section at the 2013 Cannes Film Festival.
It was released on August 16, 2013, by IFC Films.
The film received positive reviews overall, with critics praising its original take on the Bonnie
and Clyde archetype, and commending its style and western iconography influences.
It garnered numerous critical awards and nominations and was listed in the top ten films of 2013 by many
domestic and international film publications, but ultimately under-performed at the box office.
The film explores themes of river, 1970s, texas,
family relationships, prison escape.
The tone is emotional.